Hachikuji!
It's been so long!
You're so damn cute!
Let me touch you! Let me hug you!
Ooh, I'm gonna see your panties!
Oww!
The hell are you doing?!
Don't worry, I'm not an enemy!
Calm down! Take a deep breath!
You breathe like a Terminator.
It's me! Me! Take a good look!
Oh, it's Muraragi-san.
Don't call people things that sound so unsatisfying.
Sorry, I stuttered.
No, you did it on purpose.
I bit my tongue!
It wasn't on purpose?!
God is with us.
What miracle happened to you?!
So you've been studying for your exams?
Well, I can get help from the valedictorian and the 7th-best.
Honestly, I'm invincible.
Hanekawa-san's the one with braids that I met, right?
Yeah.
And Senjougahara-san's your girlfriend.
Got a problem with that?
I figured you'd go for Hanekawa-san between the two of them.
It seems kind of weird that you'd pick Senjougahara-san.
Why I'd...
I don't think of Hanekawa like that.
I owe her too much, and she'd probably shoot me down anyway.
Plus I'm into Senjougahara, despite her personality.
Well, if you say you prefer Senjougahara-san,
I guess that's right. It takes all kinds.
I guess.
It's "everyone has a type", isn't it?
By the way, Araragi.
About that vampire.
Um... She's going by Oshino Shinobu-san now, right?
Looks about eight, blonde, with a helmet and goggles?
What about her?
I wasn't able to get close so I can't be sure,
but I think I saw her around yesterday.
At around five at night,
at the donut shop by the highway.
Donuts, huh.
Would Oshino really let her go out alone like that?
Yeah, I thought the same thing.
I thought I should tell you, so I waited for you here.
Really? Why didn't you say so sooner?
I'm sorry.
Some pedo came up to me and started groping me.
I was so shocked that I forgot all about it.
Oh, really? Sorry I gave you the wrong idea.
I'm just glad I could help you out.
Anyway, do you have the time?
Oh, right.
Later, Hachikuji.
Sure. I know we'll meet again.
Oh my.
Where are you going, Araragi-kun?
Not far.
What are you going to do?
Volunteering.
I see.
Very well. Go ahead, Araragi-kun.
I'll take pity on you and answer roll call for you.
Do it for me?
I'll say it in your voice, so it should be fine.
Leave it to me.
My voice actress is excellent.
Voice actress?!
What is this, an anime?!
You're so beautiful, Hitagi-san.
The woman I've always dreamed of. I love you.
How was it? Pretty good?
Not even close! I'd been looking forward to it, but it doesn't even match what I imagined!
I haven't even said anything like that yet!
"Yet". So you plan on it in the future?
Yeah!
Hey, Hanekawa!
Araragi-kun!
You're not supposed to ride your bike in the park.
There's parking for it.
This is no time to worry about that!
We're skipping school, quit worrying about biking.
They're completely different problems.
Just hurry up and stop.
Sorry to make you skip school, Araragi-kun.
No problem.
Did you think I was angry? I wasn't trying to be sarcastic.
Don't worry, I planned it all out.
You won't have any trouble being absent from today's classes.
But what's going to happen to the preparations for the arts festival with the organizers gone?
I'm having Senjougahara-san take care of things after school.
Isn't that a mistake?
She took yesterday off.
So it's only fair.
These have to be her pajamas.
Hey, Hanekawa.
What?
No, Hanekawa-sama.
Sama?
Let me take your shirt.
Araragi-kun.
Yes?
You're making me angry.
Sorry.
Okay, I'm done joking around.
What's wrong, Hanekawa?
Those headaches again?
No, I'm feeling better now.
Araragi-kun... About Golden Week...
I remembered something.
Oh.
No, it's not that.
I feel like I'm remembering something I forgot.
I see.
A cat.
It's a cat.
I remembered that.
The cat we buried together.
I remembered it.
But you didn't just call me out here because you remembered it.
Yeah.
An aberration, huh...
So I'd like you to show me how to get to Oshino-san's place.
Can you show me the way?
Of course.
... Of course. But can I ask you a couple questions first?
I guess. Why?
I've been leaning too hard on Oshino to fix aberrations for me.
Even if I end up making it his problem,
I want to have a handle on it first.
Okay.
Fine, go ahead and ask.
You said you've had lots of headaches lately. When exactly did they start?
Around a month ago.
Yesterday and the day before were both when I was with you,
and I've had them pretty bad at the bookstore and in front of school too.
You should have told me then!
Sorry.
I didn't want to make you worry.
Oh well, don't worry about it.
So, after Golden Week,
has anything happened to you involving cats?
Something involving cats?
Even just a black cat crossing your path.
On May 27th,
the radio show I listen to at night read a letter from someone named "Big Bear Cat".
Do you think that's related?
No, I don't.
Speaking of which, this is what it said.
People in comics and anime seem to have it really easy,
but being a maid must be incredibly stressful work.
They don't have any time to rest.
I heard this at a mixer recently, and it's right on the money.
You don't need to go into that much detail.
By the way, Araragi-kun. Don't you think there was something funny about that letter?
I can't quite put my finger on it, though.
Um... He heard that maids never have any spare time,
from someone he met at a relaxed mixer.
That's funny.
Why did you even need to tell me about that letter?!
Oh, I see. I didn't quite get it the first time.
Plus, if you think hard about it, a "Big Bear Cat" isn't a cat, it's a panda!
Oh, you're right.
Anything else?
Anything?
Well... On the same show, there was a guy named "the Posturing Waggler".
"Lately, when I've played President with my friends,"
"after someone deals, one of them keeps saying things."
"Things like 'when I was in middle school, 4 was the highest card'."
What's funny about this?
When I asked whether there was anything else, I didn't mean any more hard-to-understand letters.
Plus, about that letter, in President there's all sorts of weird rules
like "8s go out of turn" or "anyone who's no longer President becomes the Asshole".
The joke is that they pick the best rules for the hand they've drawn.
Oh, I see! I knew you'd get it.
You thanking me for this doesn't make me happy.
Also, about the pen name "the Posturing Waggler",
"Posturing" and "Waggler" are written with the same kanji, so it's a bad pun.
But not all the letters to the show are that hard to understand.
Someone named "Walk toward the apple" wrote.
"Yesterday a friend and I went to a video rental place."
"We wanted to rent the DVDs of a certain serial drama,"
"but someone else had volume 8 out,"
"so we were only able to watch up to volume 7."
"My friend said 'volume 7 makes it seem like it ends in 8.'"
"'The person who has volume 8 out now must be chuckling.'"
"I think the person who rented volume 8 is playing Sevens."
That's pretty funny, but quit talking about the radio!
Anyway.
Next question, Hanekawa.
Will you take off your hat?
That...  That's not a question, Araragi-kun.
Really?
Really.
Hanekawa-sama, let me take your hat.
Araragi-kun.
Yes?
You're making me angry.
Then be angry.
If you want to be angry, go right ahead.
I care more about my debt to you than our friendship.
What do you mean, your debt to me?
Spring break.
That... But that's...
Didn't you just save yourself?
No.
Oshino may say so,
but I think you saved me.
I owe you my life.
I want to do something for you in return.
If I do, even if you get angry or hate me, I can take it.
Take it, huh.
That's pretty saucy.
Really?
Coming from you, it's saucy.
That's something a bully would say.
I didn't expect to hear it from a star pupil.
Yeah.
Don't laugh.
Are you done yet?
Ah, yeah.
Thanks.
Why are you thanking me?
Well... Okay, yeah.
It feels like Golden Week again.
If it's that, we can deal with it.
Yeah.
All right.
Let's go to Oshino's.
Don't tell me you're going to complain that doubling up on a bike is against the law?
I kind of want to, but I'll let it slide.
I made you skip school, so it's fair.
Isn't calling that a fair trade kind of weird?
All right, get on.
Let's go.
They're soft.
And big!
Araragi-kun.
There's something we need to talk about after we get off the bike.
All right, let's get going.
Even still, it must be so much trouble for you.
You have to take care of so many people.
So many people?
Like Senjougahara-san, and Mayoi-chan, and Kanbaru-san,
and Sengoku-chan yesterday.
They're all girls, huh.
Shut up.
And always with aberrations, now that I think of it.
It seems like you're not done yet.
That's right.
There's no way Senjougahara-san really recovered that quickly.
It started when you were attacked by a vampire over spring break.
That's when it all began.
The aberrations themselves were always there.
It's not like they just showed up one day.
Did you know, Araragi-kun?
Know what?
One of the special powers of vampires.
They captivate humans with their charm.
Captivate?
It's like hypnotism.
One gaze into those eyes can captivate someone for life.
So what?
Nothing, just a thought I had.
Maybe it has something to do
with why you're so popular with the girls all of a sudden.
Sorry, I'm just teasing.
Don't worry.
If anything, it helps me understand.
Charm, huh.
You know everything.
I don't know everything.
I don't know anything...
Hey, it's Araragi-kun.
And the class prez, right?
Her hair's different, but with those glasses it's gotta be her.
Long time no see, Prez.
Araragi-kun, I saw you yesterday.
What, can't you say "I've been waiting" or "I stayed up waiting"?
Nothing like that today?
Huh? Really?
What's up, Prez?
You have today off?
I don't really think he's trying to sabotage you.
Oh, that's it?
Must be the Foundation Day I've heard about.
Well, no.
A cap?
That cap looks good on you.
Thanks.
So that's what you're up to, Araragi-kun?
You really can't even take three steps without getting in trouble.
Anyway, come on in.
To be honest, I'm really busy right now, Araragi-kun.
I'm so busy I don't have any spare time.
I see.
Oh well, I don't mind.
You're you, but I've gotta be a bit accomodating if Prez comes to me with a problem.
A meddlecat.
It has to be considered one of the three legendary cat spirits.
You're you, but I don't even need to tell this to Prez, do I?
Hey, stop it with the "You're you, but" when you mention Hanekawa.
It's starting to get to me.
I'm not doing it on purpose.
I just can't tell a lie.
You'd better keep your eyes open at night.
Don't worry. I'm a night owl.
Cats are night owls, too.
Hanekawa?!
Don't get worked up, Araragi-kun.
It's quite nice.
Isn't it a good thing?
Getting to see Prez's cat ears,
getting to see her in her pajamas,
Don't judge me like that!
You're misunderstanding!
It's not a misunderstanding, is it?
If anything, you should thank me for giving you an excuse to bike the whole way here
with Prez's arms wrapped around you.
You've already scouted out the situation, haven't you.
What happened with the shy girl the day before yesterday must have woken you up.
So Sengoku's a shy girl?
Anyway, what's happening?
With what you've learned, I don't really have anything to do.
I'm gonna skip a step here.
Skip a step?
There's no time, right?
And it's quicker to ask her herself than bother Prez.
Herself?
But...
Yeah.
Here she comes, Araragi-kun.
Here comes the sex kitten.
So we meet again, human. I'm amazed.
And it looks like you haven't been punished for lusting after my myaster's boobs.
You're always such a bad boy, meow.
Do you want to be eaten up?
I'm Karen!
I'm Tsukihi!
Hey, about baseball.
About baseball?
You can't question the ump, can you?
You can't.
The ump's judgments are absolute!
But you can try to fast-talk him.
Fast-talk him?
Hey umpire, don't pretend with me, you had to have seen that was an out.
Sometimes it works!
Cunning!
If you do it at the wrong time, you get ejected!
Get outta here, you bum!
Preview quiz!
Quiz!
Preview squeeze!
Squeeze?
Squeeze means bunting!
Bunting?
What's a safety squeze? I don't get it!
I don't get it at all! What's safe about a sacrifice bunt?
It's sacrificial! That's a paradox, make up your mind!
Being so vague makes it confusing! What's with a bunt that makes you safe by sacrificing you?!
That wasn't a quiz, that was just a complaint!
Next time, Tsubasa Cat part 4!
A bunt to advance the runner!
A failed bunt.